A Guide to the Correspondence and Subject Files of the Librarian of Virginia, 1832-2024 Jan
Library of Virginia
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1827-2007.
  - 1903-1968 (Accession 28078)., 72.45 (212 boxes)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Exhibitors Exhibit Space, 1956 (Box 157, Folder 1)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Exhibitors, Exhibit Space, 1956 (Box 157, Folder 2)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Exhibitors, Exhibit Space, 1957-1958 (Box 157, Folder 3)
    - Southeastern Library Association-General Correspondence, 1941-1945 (Box 157, Folder 4)
    - Southeastern Library Association-General Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 157, Folder 5)
    - Southeastern Library Association-General Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 158, Folder 1)
    - Southeastern Library Association-General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 158, Folder 2)
    - Southeastern Library Association- Hotel Arrangements and Reservations, 1957-1958 (Box 158, Folder 3)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Invitations, 1946 (Box 158, Folder 4)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Membership, 1956-1958 (Box 158, Folder 5)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Other Regional Associations, 1957 (Box 158, Folder 6)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Place of Meeting, 1956-1957 (Box 158, Folder 7)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Program, 1956-1958 (Box 158, Folder 8)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Public Library Section, 1957 (Box 158, Folder 9)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Report of the President, 1956-1958 (Box 159, Folder 1)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Southern Humanities Conference, 1957-1958 (Box 159, Folder 2)
    - Southeastern Library Association-Treasurer, 1957-1958 (Box 159, Folder 3)
    - Southeastern Library Association- Treasurer's Report, 1952-1958 (Box 159, Folder 4)
    - Southern Regional Conference on Education Beyond High School, 1957 (Box 159, Folder 5)
    - Southern Regional Conference on Education Beyond High School, 1955-1957 (Box 159, Folder 6)
    - Southern Regional Conference on Education Beyond High School, 1957 (Box 159, Folder 7)
    - Sydnor, Charles, S., Dr., Mailing List, Correspondence 1953, June (Box 159, Folder 8)
    - T, 1903-1906 (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - T, 1907-1908 (Box 160, Folder 2)
    - T, 1909-1910 (Box 160, Folder 3)
    - T, 1911-1912 (Box 160, Folder 4)
    - T, 1913-1914 (Box 160, Folder 5)
    - T, 1915-1916 (Box 160, Folder 6)
    - T, 1917-1918 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - T, 1919 (Box 161, Folder 2)
    - T, 1920 (Box 161, Folder 3)
    - T, 1921 (Box 161, Folder 4)
    - T, 1922 (Box 161, Folder 5)
    - T, 1923 (Box 161, Folder 6)
    - T, 1924 (Box 161, Folder 7)
    - Tr-Ty, 1924 (Box 162, Folder 1)
    - T-To, 1925 (Box 162, Folder 2)
    - Tr-Ty, 1925 (Box 162, Folder 3)
    - T, 1926 (Box 162, Folder 4)
    - T, 1927 (Box 162, Folder 5)
    - T, 1928 (Box 162, Folder 6)
    - T, 1929 (Box 162, Folder 7)
    - T-Ti, 1930 (Box 163, Folder 1)
    - To-Tz, 1930 (Box 163, Folder 2)
    - T-To, 1931 (Box 163, Folder 3)
    - Tr-Tz, 1931 (Box 163, Folder 4)
    - T, 1932 (Box 163, Folder 5)
    - T, 1933 (Box 163, Folder 6)
    - T, 1934 (Box 163, Folder 7)
    - T, 1935 (Box 163, Folder 8)
    - T, 1936 (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - T, 1937 (Box 164, Folder 2)
    - T, 1939 (Box 164, Folder 3)
    - T, 1940 (Box 164, Folder 4)
    - T, 1941 (Box 164, Folder 5)
    - T, 1942 (Box 164, Folder 6)
    - T, 1943 (Box 164, Folder 7)
    - T, 1943 (Box 164, Folder 8)
    - T, 1944 (Box 165, Folder 1)
    - T, 1945 (Box 165, Folder 2)
    - T, 1946 (Box 165, Folder 3)
    - T, 1947 (Box 165, Folder 4)
    - T, 1948 (Box 165, Folder 5)
    - T, 1949 (Box 165, Folder 6)
    - T, 1950 (Box 165, Folder 7)
    - T, 1951 (Box 165, Folder 8)
    - T, 1952 (Box 165, Folder 9)
    - T, 1953 (Box 165, Folder 10)
    - T, 1954 (Box 165, Folder 11)
    - T, 1955-1957 (Box 165, Folder 12)
    - T, 1958 (Box 165, Folder 13)
    - T, 1959 (Box 166, Folder 1)
    - T, 1960 (Box 166, Folder 2)
    - T, 1961 (Box 166, Folder 3)
    - T, 1962 (Box 166, Folder 4)
    - T, 1963 (Box 166, Folder 5)
    - T, 1964 (Box 166, Folder 6)
    - T, 1965 (Box 166, Folder 7)
    - T, 1966 (Box 166, Folder 8)
    - T, 1967 (Box 166, Folder 9)
    - T, 1968 (Box 166, Folder 10)
    - Tunstall, Robert, B., 1950 (Box 166, Folder 11)
    - Tunstall, Robert B., 1951 (Box 166, Folder 12)
    - Tunstall, Robert, B., 1952 (Box 166, Folder 13)
    - Turner, W. R., 1953-1955 (Box 167, Folder 1)
    - U, 1903-1913 (Box 167, Folder 2)
    - U, 1914-1915 (Box 167, Folder 3)
    - U, 1916 (Box 167, Folder 4)
    - U, 1917 (Box 167, Folder 5)
    - U, 1918 (Box 167, Folder 6)
    - U, 1919-1920 (Box 168, Folder 1)
    - U, 1921-1922 (Box 168, Folder 2)
    - U, 1923-1934 (Box 168, Folder 3)
    - U, 1925-1926 (Box 168, Folder 4)
    - U, 1927-1928 (Box 168, Folder 5)
    - U, 1929-1930 (Box 169, Folder 1)
    - U, 1931 (Box 169, Folder 2)
    - U, 1932-1933 (Box 169, Folder 3)
    - U, 1934 (Box 169, Folder 4)
    - U, 1935 (Box 169, Folder 5)
    - U, 1936 (Box 170, Folder 1)
    - U, 1937 (Box 170, Folder 2)
    - U, 1938 (Box 170, Folder 3)
    - U, 1939 (Box 170, Folder 4)
    - U, 1940 (Box 170, Folder 5)
    - U, 1941 (Box 170, Folder 6)
    - U, 1942 (Box 170, Folder 7)
    - U, 1943 (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - U, 1944 (Box 171, Folder 2)
    - U, 1945 (Box 171, Folder 3)
    - U, 1946 (Box 171, Folder 4)
    - U, 1947 (Box 171, Folder 5)
    - U, 1948 (Box 171, Folder 6)
    - U, 1949 (Box 171, Folder 7)
    - U, 1950 (Box 172, Folder 1)
    - U, 1951 (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - U, 1952 (Box 172, Folder 3)
    - U, 1953 (Box 172, Folder 4)
    - U, 1954 (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - U, 1955-1956 (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - U, 1957 (Box 173, Folder 1)
    - U, 1958 (Box 173, Folder 2)
    - U, 1959 (Box 173, Folder 3)
    - U, 1960 (Box 173, Folder 4)
    - U, 1961 (Box 173, Folder 5)
    - U, 1962 (Box 173, Folder 6)
    - U, 1963 (Box 174, Folder 1)
    - U, 1964 (Box 174, Folder 2)
    - U, 1965 (Box 174, Folder 3)
    - U, 1966 (Box 174, Folder 4)
    - U, 1967 (Box 174, Folder 5)
    - U, 1968 (Box 175, Folder 1)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, 1956 (Box 175, Folder 2)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, May-June, 1957 (Box 175, Folder 3)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, July, 1957 (Box 175, Folder 4)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, August, 1957 (Box 175, Folder 5)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, September-December, 1957 (Box 175, Folder 6)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, January-April, 1958 (Box 175, Folder 7)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, May-August, 1958 (Box 175, Folder 8)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, September-December, 1958 (Box 176, Folder 1)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, January-April, 1959 (Box 176, Folder 2)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, May-August, 1959 (Box 176, Folder 3)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, September-December, 1959 (Box 176, Folder 4)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, January-March, 1960 (Box 176, Folder 5)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, April-June, 1960 (Box 177, Folder 1)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, July-August, 1960 (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, September-December, 1960 (Box 177, Folder 3)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, January-April, 1961 (Box 177, Folder 4)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, May-August, 1961 (Box 177, Folder 5)
    - United Service Organization-United Fund of Virginia, September-December, 1961 (Box 177, Folder 6)
    - United Service Department of Defense, 1940-1942 (Box 178, Folder 1)
    - United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare, January-February, 1967 (Box 178, Folder 2)
    - United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1967 (Box 178, Folder 3)
    - United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1967 (Box 178, Folder 4)
    - United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1967 (Box 178, Folder 5)
    - V, 1903-1913 (Box 178, Folder 6)
    - V, 1914-1915 (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - V, 1916-1917 (Box 179, Folder 2)
    - V, 1918-1919 (Box 179, Folder 3)
    - V, 1920-1922 (Box 179, Folder 4)
    - V, 1923 (Box 179, Folder 5)
    - V, 1924 (Box 179, Folder 6)
    - V, 1925 (Box 179, Folder 7)
    - V, 1926 (Box 180, Folder 1)
    - V, 1927 (Box 180, Folder 2)
    - V, 1928 (Box 180, Folder 3)
    - V, 1929 (Box 180, Folder 4)
    - V, 1930 (Box 180, Folder 5)
    - V, 1931 (Box 180, Folder 6)
    - V, 1932 (Box 181, Folder 1)
    - V, 1933 (Box 181, Folder 2)
    - V, 1933 (Box 181, Folder 3)
    - V, 1934 (Box 181, Folder 4)
    - V, 1935 (Box 181, Folder 5)
    - V, 1936 (Box 181, Folder 6)
    - V, 1937 (Box 182, Folder 1)
    - V, 1938 (Box 182, Folder 2)
    - V, 1939 (Box 182, Folder 3)
    - V, 1940 (Box 182, Folder 4)
    - V, 1941 (Box 182, Folder 5)
    - V, 1942 (Box 182, Folder 6)
    - V, 1943 (Box 183, Folder 1)
    - V, 1944 (Box 183, Folder 2)
    - V, 1945 (Box 183, Folder 3)
    - V, 1946 (Box 183, Folder 4)
    - V, 1947 (Box 183, Folder 5)
    - V, 1948 (Box 183, Folder 6)
    - V, 1949 (Box 183, Folder 7)
    - V, 1950 (Box 184, Folder 1)
    - V, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 2)
    - V, 1952 (Box 184, Folder 3)
    - V, 1953 (Box 184, Folder 4)
    - V, 1954 (Box 184, Folder 5)
    - V, 1955 (Box 184, Folder 6)
    - V, 1956 (Box 185, Folder 1)
    - V, 1956 (Box 185, Folder 2)
    - V, 1957 (Box 185, Folder 3)
    - V, 1957 (Box 185, Folder 4)
    - V, 1958 (Box 185, Folder 5)
    - V, 1959 (Box 185, Folder 6)
    - V, 1960 (Box 185, Folder 7)
    - V, 1961 (Box 186, Folder 1)
    - V, 1962 (Box 186, Folder 2)
    - V, 1963 (Box 186, Folder 3)
    - V, 1964 (Box 186, Folder 4)
    - V, 1965 (Box 186, Folder 5)
    - V, 1966 (Box 186, Folder 6)
    - V, 1967 (Box 186, Folder 7)
    - V, 1968 (Box 186, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Association of School Trustees, 1951-1952 (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Cavalcade, 1965 (Box 187, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1958 (Box 187, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1959 (Box 187, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1959 (Box 187, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1960 (Box 187, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1961 (Box 187, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1961 (Box 188, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1962 (Box 188, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1962 (Box 188, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1964 (Box 188, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1964 (Box 188, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1965-1966 (Box 188, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1966 (Box 189, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1966 (Box 189, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1966 (Box 189, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1967 (Box 189, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of, 1967 (Box 189, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of-Agriculutre Department, 1967 (Box 189, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of-Auditor of Public Accounts and Governor's Office, 1965 (Box 189, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of-Auditor of Public Accounts-State Council on Higher Learning, 1968 (Box 190, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of-Budget Exhibit for Dept. of Education, 1948-1958 (Box 190, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of-Budget Exhibit for Dept. of Education, 1958-1962 (Box 190, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of-Budget Division--Dept of Military Affairs, 1963 (Box 190, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of-Education--Engineering, 1968 (Box 190, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of-Fire Alarm System, 1958-1963 (Box 190, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of-Governor's Office, 1961 (Box 191, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of Governor-Highway, Dept. of, 1968 (Box 191, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of Governor-Highway Dept.--Bureau of Property Records and Insurance, 1965 (Box 191, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of Governor-History of Hornbook of Virginia, (Samples), 1947 (Box 191, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of Governor-Longwood College--Planning Division Governor's Office, 1968 (Box 191, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of Governor-Milk Commission, State--William and Mary College, 1963 (Box 191, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of Governor-Property Records--William and Mary College, 1968 (Box 191, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of Governor-Purchase and Supply--Welfare and Institution Department, 1965 (Box 192, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Commonwealth of Governor-Records Inventory Report, Waller Depot, n.d. (Box 192, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Southeastern Broadsides Before 1877, n.d. (Box 192, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Southeastern Broadsides Before 1877, n.d. (Box 192, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Southeastern Broadsides Before 1877, 1970 circa (Box 192, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Southeastern Broadsides Before 1877 Negatives, n.d. (Box 192, Folder 6)
    - Virginia's World War II History Commission, 1944 (Box 192, Folder 7)
    - Virginia's World War II History Commission, 1945 (Box 192, Folder 8)
    - Virginia's World War II History Commission, 1946 (Box 192, Folder 9)
    - Virginia's World War II History Commission, 1947 (Box 193, Folder 1)
    - Virginia's World War II History Commission, 1948 (Box 193, Folder 2)
    - Virginia's World War II History Commission, 1949 (Box 193, Folder 3)
    - Virginia's World War II History Commission Minutes, 1946-1948 (Box 193, Folder 4)
    - Virginia's World War II History Division, 1949 (Box 193, Folder 5)
    - W, 1903-1908 (Box 194, Folder 6)
    - W, 1909 (Box 194, Folder 1)
    - W, 1910 (Box 194, Folder 2)
    - W, 1911 (Box 194, Folder 3)
    - W, 1912 (Box 194, Folder 4)
    - W, 1913 (Box 194, Folder 5)
    - W, 1914 (Box 194, Folder 6)
    - W, 1914 (Box 194, Folder 7)
    - W, 1915 (Box 195, Folder 1)
    - W, 1915 (Box 195, Folder 2)
    - W, 1916 (Box 195, Folder 3)
    - W, 1916 (Box 195, Folder 4)
    - W, 1917 (Box 195, Folder 5)
    - W, 1918 (Box 195, Folder 6)
    - W, 1919 (Box 195, Folder 7)
    - W, 1919 (Box 195, Folder 8)
    - W, 1920 (Box 196, Folder 1)
    - W, 1920 (Box 196, Folder 2)
    - W, 1921 (Box 196, Folder 3)
    - W, 1922 (Box 196, Folder 4)
    - W, 1923 (Box 196, Folder 5)
    - W, 1923 (Box 196, Folder 6)
    - W, 1924 (Box 196, Folder 7)
    - W, 1924 (Box 197, Folder 1)
    - W, 1925 (Box 197, Folder 2)
    - W, 1926 (Box 197, Folder 3)
    - W-Wh, 1927 (Box 197, Folder 4)
    - Wi-Wz, 1927 (Box 197, Folder 5)
    - W-Wh, 1928 (Box 197, Folder 6)
    - Wi-Wz, 1928 (Box 197, Folder 7)
    - W-Wh, 1929 (Box 198, Folder 1)
    - Wi-Wz, 1929 (Box 198, Folder 2)
    - Wa, 1930 (Box 198, Folder 3)
    - We, 1930 (Box 198, Folder 4)
    - Wh, 1930 (Box 198, Folder 5)
    - Wi, 1930 (Box 198, Folder 6)
    - Wo-Wz, 1930 (Box 199, Folder 1)
    - Wa, 1931 (Box 199, Folder 2)
    - We, 1931 (Box 199, Folder 3)
    - Wh-Wz, 1931 (Box 199, Folder 4)
    - W-We, 1932 (Box 199, Folder 5)
    - Wh-Wi, 1932 (Box 199, Folder 6)
    - Wo-Wz, 1932 (Box 200, Folder 1)
    - Wa, 1933 (Box 200, Folder 2)
    - We-Wh, 1933 (Box 200, Folder 3)
    - Wi, 1933 (Box 200, Folder 4)
    - Wo-Wz, 1933 (Box 200, Folder 5)
    - W-Wh, 1934 (Box 200, Folder 6)
    - Wi, 1934 (Box 200, Folder 7)
    - Wo-Wz, 1934 (Box 201, Folder 1)
    - Wa, 1935 (Box 201, Folder 2)
    - We-Wh, 1935 (Box 201, Folder 3)
    - Wi, 1935 (Box 201, Folder 4)
    - Wo-Wz, 1935 (Box 201, Folder 5)
    - W-We, 1936 (Box 201, Folder 6)
    - Wh-Wi, 1936 (Box 201, Folder 7)
    - Wo-Wz, 1936 (Box 201, Folder 8)
    - W-Wh, 1937 (Box 202, Folder 1)
    - Wi-Wz, 1937 (Box 202, Folder 2)
    - Wa-Wh, 1938 (Box 202, Folder 3)
    - Wi, 1938 (Box 202, Folder 4)
    - Wo-Wz, 1938 (Box 202, Folder 5)
    - W-Wh, 1939 (Box 202, Folder 6)
    - Wi, 1939 (Box 202, Folder 7)
    - Wo-Wz, 1939 (Box 203, Folder 1)
    - W-We, 1940 (Box 203, Folder 2)
    - Wi-Wz, 1940 (Box 203, Folder 3)
    - W-Wh, 1941 (Box 203, Folder 4)
    - Wi-Wz, 1941 (Box 203, Folder 5)
    - W-Wh, 1942 (Box 203, Folder 6)
    - Wi-Wy, 1942 (Box 203, Folder 7)
    - Wa-Wh, 1943 (Box 203, Folder 8)
    - Wi-Wz, 1943 (Box 203, Folder 9)
    - W, 1944 (Box 204, Folder 1)
    - W-Wh, 1945 (Box 204, Folder 2)
    - Wi-Wy, 1945 (Box 204, Folder 3)
    - W, 1946 (Box 204, Folder 4)
    - W-Wh, 1947 (Box 204, Folder 5)
    - Wi-Wy, 1947 (Box 204, Folder 6)
    - W-Wh, 1948 (Box 204, Folder 7)
    - Wi-Wy, 1948 (Box 204, Folder 8)
    - W, 1949 (Box 204, Folder 9)
    - Wa-Wh, 1950 (Box 204, Folder 10)
    - Wi-Wy, 1950 (Box 204, Folder 11)
    - W, 1951 (Box 204, Folder 12)
    - W, 1952 (Box 204, Folder 13)
    - W, 1953 (Box 204, Folder 14)
    - W 1954 (Box 205, Folder 1)
    - W, 1955 (Box 205, Folder 2)
    - W, 1956 (Box 205, Folder 3)
    - W, 1957 (Box 205, Folder 4)
    - W-Wh, 1958 (Box 205, Folder 5)
    - Wi-Wo, 1958 (Box 205, Folder 6)
    - W, 1959 (Box 205, Folder 7)
    - W, 1960 (Box 205, Folder 8)
    - W, 1961 (Box 206, Folder 1)
    - W, 1962 (Box 206, Folder 2)
    - W, 1962 (Box 206, Folder 3)
    - W, 1963 (Box 206, Folder 4)
    - W, 1964 (Box 206, Folder 5)
    - W, 1965 (Box 206, Folder 6)
    - W, 1966 (Box 206, Folder 7)
    - W, 1967 (Box 206, Folder 8)
    - W, 1968 (Box 207, Folder 1)
    - War Bond, 1944-1945 (Box 207, Folder 2)
    - Wilson, Henry, Harrison, 1931 (Box 207, Folder 3)
    - XYZ, 1903-1915 (Box 207, Folder 4)
    - XYZ, 1916-1921 (Box 207, Folder 5)
    - XYZ, 1922-1930 (Box 207, Folder 6)
    - XYZ, 1931-1932 (Box 207, Folder 7)
    - XYZ, 1934-1937 (Box 207, Folder 8)
    - XYZ, 1938-1939 (Box 207, Folder 9)
    - XYZ, 1940-1952 (Box 207, Folder 10)
    - XYZ, 1953-1967 (Box 207, Folder 11)
  - 1904-1969 (Accession 42652)., 1.22 cu. ft. (4 boxes)
    Accession 42652 consists of correspondence to and from the State Librarian and the State Library Board. The State Librarians addressed in this collection are: H. R. McIllwaine, Wilmer L. Hall, and Randolph W. Church, board members include: Pendleton, Powell, Roberson, Sale, Stuart, Tunstall (bulk), Tyler, Wilkerson, Williams, Wyatt.
    This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Pendleton, E., 1918-1922. (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
    - Powell, L., 1954-1964. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Robertson, W., 1949-1959. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sale, E., 1962-1969. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Stuart, W., 1952-1962. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Tunstall, R., 1935-1940. (Box 1, Folder 8-11)
    - Tunstall, R., 1940-1949. (Box 2)
    - Tunstall, R., 1947-1949. (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Tyler, L., 1915-1935. (Box 1, Folder 3-8)
    - Wilkerson, W., 1960-1966. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Williams, R., 1933-1936. (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
    - Wyatt, E., 1952-1961. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - State Board of Education, 1930-1935. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1904-1948. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1917-1918; 1933-1971 (Bulk 1938-1940) (Accession 28771)., 1.7 cu. ft. (5 boxes)
    Accession 28771 consists of correspondence to and from the State Librarian, the majority of which deals with federal programs which were designed to create employment durring the Great Depression, such as, the Work Projects Administration, Emergency Relief Administration, and the Federal Civil Works Administration. These programs funded projects which enabled Virginia libraries to catalog, index, repair, survey collections and create mobile libraries, or bookmobiles. Other files pertain to the conservation of food during World War One, the gift of John Stewart Bryan's private library (Bryan was the President of Richmond Newspaper, Inc.), the Commission on National Archives Survey, the International Congress of Archives, as well as, newspaper and microfilm holdings. The State Librarians addressed in this collection are: H. R. McIllwaine, Wilmer L. Hall, and Randolph W. Church.
    This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title, pages within folders are filed in reverse chronolgical order.
    - Bryan Library, 1951-1952. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Civil Works Administration, 1933-1934. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Commission on National Archives Survey, 1934. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Emergency Relief Administration, 1933-1934. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Interagency Committee on Recreation, 1955-1960. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - International Congress on Archives, 1960. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Lanham Act, 1942-1943. (Box 1a, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper and Microfilm, 1941-1950. (Box 1a, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper and Microfilm, 1951-1971. (Box 1a, Folder 3)
    - Public Records of Virginia - Replevin, 1947-1951. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Relief Projects - 119-F7-121, 1934-1935. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Relief Projects - Archival Survey, 1934-1935. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Relief Projects - Work Projects Administration, 1933-1937. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - United States Food Administration - Food Conservation, 1917-1918. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - United States Food Administration - Sugar Conservation, 1917-1918. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Work Projects Administration - Basic Materials, 1938-1940. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Work Projects Administration - Charlotte County, 1939-1940. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Work Projects Administration - Current, 1939-1942. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Work Projects Administration - Fairfax and Loudoun Counties, 1939-1941. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Work Projects Administration - Non-current (1 of 2), 1938-1939. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Work Projects Administration - Non-current (2 of 2), 1938-1939. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Work Projects Administration - Non-current, 1940-1941. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Work Projects Administration - Pittsylvania County Library, 1939-1940. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Work Projects Administration - Program Proposal, 1942. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Work Projects Administration - Sponsor's Contribution, 1938-1941. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Work Projects Administration - Tidewater Regional Library, 1939-1940. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1952-1962 (Accession 28179)., .7 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
    Box 1 contains the correspondence of State Librarian, Randolph W. Church in regard to the lamination of aging documents. Correspondents include by are not limited to; Library of Congress, National Archives and Records Administration, National Bureau of Standards, and William "Bill" Barrow head of the conservation laboratory at the state library. The Virginia State Library, Library of Congress and National Bureau of Standards collaborated on developing a process to preserve aging documents by lamination. The lamination process consisted of pressing documents between two thin layers of cellulose acetate, which also contains stabilizers, plasticizer and impurities. This process was used on many documents at the state library as part of the Lamination Project. 1958-1959 contains many letters which discuss the debate as to the effectiveness and longevity of the lamination process, and by 1962 there were letters between Church and Barrow as to the cause of the odd acidic smell emitted by documents which had been laminated. Included are invoices, drafts, research reports, payment reciepts.